{"version":1,"data":{"1":{"category":"ACCOUNTING BASIC","question_set":[{"qID":"1.0|easy","question":"The financial statement that reports the revenues and expenses for a period of time such as a year or a month is the ?","selection":["Balance Sheet","Income Statement","Statement of cash flow"],"answer":"Income Statement"},{"qID":"1.1|easy","question":"Under the accrual basis of accounting, revenues are reported in the accounting period when the   ?","selection":["Cash is Received","Service or Goods have been Delivered","Income is received"],"answer":"Service or Goods have been Delivered"},{"qID":"1.2|easy","question":"Resources owned by a company (such as cash, accounts receivable, vehicles) are reported on the balance sheet and are referred to as __________.?","selection":["Asset","Liabilities","Owners Equity"],"answer":"Asset"},{"qID":"1.3|easy","question":"Obligations (amounts owed) are reported on the balance sheet and are referred to as ________? ","selection":["Asset","Liabilities","Capital"],"answer":"Liabilities"},{"qID":"1.4|easy","question":"Unearned Revenues is what type of account ? ","selection":["Asset","Liability","Stockholders(Owners)Equity"],"answer":"Liability"},{"qID":"1.5|easy","question":"The listing of all of the accounts available for use in a company's accounting system is known as the__________ ? ","selection":["Account title","Chart of Account","Account Receivable"],"answer":" Chart of Account"},{"qID":"1.6|easy","question":"Which term is associated with \"left\" or \"left-side\" ?","selection":["Debit","Credit","Asset"],"answer":" Debit"},{"qID":"1.7|easy","question":"Which term is associated with \"right\" or \"right-side\" ?","selection":["Credit","Liability","Debit"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"1.8|easy","question":"Revenues minus expenses equals __________ ?","selection":["Net income","Net Expense","Net Capital"],"answer":" Net income"},{"qID":"1.9|easy","question":"The Asset statement that reports the assets, liabilities, and stockholders' (owner's) equity at a specific date is the ?","selection":["Balance Sheet","Income Statement","Statement of cash flow"],"answer":"Balance Sheet"}]},"2":{"category":"DEBITS AND CREDITS","question_set":[{"qID":"2.0|easy","question":"Use the following information for questions 1 and 2: A company receives $500 of cash as an additional investment in the company by its owner, Mary Smith. The company's Cash account is increased and Mary Smith, Capital is increased. Should the $500 entry to the Cash account be a debit? ","selection":["Yes","No","Maybe"],"answer":"Yes"},{"qID":"2.1|easy","question":"Use the following information for questions 1 and 2: A company receives $500 of cash as an additional investment in the company by its owner, Mary Smith. The company's Cash account is increased and Mary Smith, Capital is increased. Should the $500 entry to Mary Smith, Capital be a debit?","selection":["Yes ","No","Maybe "],"answer":"No"},{"qID":"2.2|easy","question":"Generally when an expense is involved in a transaction, an expense will be","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Debited"},{"qID":"2.3|easy","question":"Generally when revenues are involved in a transaction, a revenue account will be","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"},{"qID":"2.4|easy","question":"The accountant's word to indicate that an entry will be recorded on the left-side of an account is ","selection":["Debit","Credit","None of the above"],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"2.5|easy","question":"A contra-liability account such as Discount on Notes Payable will likely have which balance?","selection":["Debit","Credit","None of the above"],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"2.6|easy","question":"A contra-asset account such as Accumulated Depreciation will likely have which balance?","selection":["Debit","Credit","None of the above "],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"2.7|easy","question":"Michel Auditor drawing account increase by P800.","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Debited"},{"qID":"2.8|easy","question":"Prepaid insurance account decrease","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"},{"qID":"2.9|easy","question":"Cash in bank account decrease by P8450","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"}]},"3":{"category":"CHART OF ACCOUNT","question_set":[{"qID":"3.0|easy","question":"The chart of accounts is a listing of the accounts presently having balances in the general ledger.","selection":["True","False","Maybe"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"3.1|easy","question":"Some accounting software will classify some accounts as \"income\" accounts, while accountants might refer to these accounts as \"revenue\" accounts.","selection":["True ","False","Maybe "],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"3.2|easy","question":"The digits of the account numbers assigned to general ledger accounts often have significance. For example, an account number beginning with a \"1\" might signify that the account is an asset account, a \"6\" might signify an operating expense, etc.","selection":["True","False","Maybe"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"3.3|easy","question":"Generally when revenues are involved in a transaction, a revenue account will be","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"},{"qID":"3.4|easy","question":"The accountant's word to indicate that an entry will be recorded on the left-side of an account is ","selection":["Debit","Credit","None of the above"],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"3.5|easy","question":"A contra-liability account such as Discount on Notes Payable will likely have which balance?","selection":["Debit","Credit","None of the above"],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"3.6|easy","question":"A contra-asset account such as Accumulated Depreciation will likely have which balance?","selection":["Debit","Credit","None of the above "],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"3.7|easy","question":"Michel Auditor drawing account increase by P800.","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Debited"},{"qID":"3.8|easy","question":"Prepaid insurance account decrease","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"},{"qID":"3.9|easy","question":"Cash in bank account decrease by P8450","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"}]},"4":{"category":"BOOKKEEPING","question_set":[{"qID":"4.0|easy","question":"The two main methods of bookkeeping and accounting are 1) the cash method, and 2) the __________method.","selection":["Depreciation","Accruals","Accumulated Depreciation"],"answer":"Accruals"},{"qID":"4.1|easy","question":"__________-entry bookkeeping means that every transaction will affect two or more accounts.","selection":["Triple ","Single","Double"],"answer":"Double"},{"qID":"4.2|easy","question":"A __________ amount will appear on the left side of a T-account.","selection":["Debit","Credit","Trial balance"],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"4.3|easy","question":"When a check is written, a cash account should be __________.","selection":["Debited","Credited","Equal"],"answer":"Credited"},{"qID":"4.4|easy","question":"Liability accounts will normally have __________ balances. ","selection":["Equal","Credit","Debit"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"4.5|easy","question":"Revenue accounts will normally have __________ balances.","selection":["Debit","Equal","Credit"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"4.6|easy","question":"Accrued expenses are likely to pertain to transactions that have ALREADY been paid.","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"4.7|easy","question":"Deferred revenues likely involve cash amounts that have NOT YET been received.","selection":["Maybe","False","True"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"4.8|easy","question":"A supplier of goods or services is known as a VENDOR.","selection":["Maybe","False","True"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"4.9|easy","question":"The book of original entry is the definition of a LEDGER.","selection":["True","False ","Maybe"],"answer":"False"}]},"5":{"category":"ACCOUNTING EQUATION","question_set":[{"qID":"5.0|easy","question":"The basic accounting equation is Assets = Liabilities + (Owner’s equity or Stockholder’s equity (if  a corporation)  Net asset (if noneprofit organization ))","selection":["True","False","Maybe"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"5.1|easy","question":"The accounting equation should remain in balance because every transaction affects how many accounts?","selection":["Only one ","Only two","Two or more "],"answer":"Two or more"},{"qID":"5.2|easy","question":"A corporation's net income is eventually recorded in the following stockholders' equity account:RETAINED EARNINGS","selection":["True","False","Maybe"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"5.3|easy","question":"The financial statement that reports the portion of change in owner's equity resulting from revenues and expenses during a specified time interval is the FINANCIAL STATEMENT","selection":["False","True","Maybe"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"5.4|easy","question":"The financial statement with a structure that is similar to the accounting equation is the BALANCE SHEET","selection":["Maybe","True","False"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"5.5|easy","question":"A corporation's quarterly DIVIDENDS will cause a reduction in the corporation's retained earnings, which in turn reduces the corporation's stockholders' equity. However, this will not reduce the corporation's net income. ","selection":["True","False","Maybe"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"5.6|easy","question":"Which of the following will cause owner's equity to increase?","selection":["Expenses","Owners Draws","Revenue "],"answer":"Revenue"},{"qID":"5.7|easy","question":"Which of the following will cause owner's equity to decrease?","selection":["Net income","Net loss","Revenue"],"answer":"Net loss"},{"qID":"5.8|easy","question":"Prepaid insurance account decrease","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"},{"qID":"5.9|easy","question":"Cash in bank account decrease by P8450","selection":["Debited","Credited","None of the above"],"answer":"Credited"}]},"6":{"category":"ACCOUNTING PRINCIPLES","question_set":[{"qID":"6.0|easy","question":"The personal assets of the owner of a company will not appear on the company's balance sheet because of which principle/guideline?","selection":["Cost","Economic Entity","Monetary Unit"],"answer":"Economic Entity"},{"qID":"6.1|easy","question":"Which principle/guideline requires a company's balance sheet to report its land at the amount the company paid to acquire the land, even if the land could be sold today at a significantly higher amount?","selection":["Cost ","Economic Entity","Monetary Unit "],"answer":"Cost"},{"qID":"6.2|easy","question":"Which principle/guideline allows a company to ignore the change in the purchasing power of the dollar over time?","selection":["Cost","Economic Entity","Monetary Unit"],"answer":"Monetary Unit"},{"qID":"6.3|easy","question":"A retailer wishes to report its merchandise inventory on its balance sheet at its retail value. This would violate which accounting principle/guideline?","selection":["Cost","Full Disclosure","Monetary Unit"],"answer":"Cost"},{"qID":"6.4|easy","question":"Which principle/guideline directs a company to show all the expenses related to its revenues of a specified period even if the expenses were not paid in that period?","selection":["Cost","Matching","Monetary Unit"],"answer":"Matching"},{"qID":"6.5|easy","question":"Which principle/guideline is associated with the assumption that the company will continue on long enough to carry out its objectives and commitments?","selection":["Economic Entity","Going Concern","Time Period"],"answer":"Going Concern"},{"qID":"6.6|easy","question":"Accrual accounting is based on this principle/guideline.","selection":["Cost","Full Disclosure","Matching"],"answer":"Matching"},{"qID":"6.7|easy","question":"Which principle/guideline justifies a company violating an accounting principle because the amounts are immaterial?","selection":["Materiality","Economic Entity","Full Disclosure"],"answer":"Materiality"},{"qID":"6.8|easy","question":"Which principle/guideline requires the company's financial statements to have footnotes containing information that is important to users of the financial statements?","selection":["Conservatism","Economic Entity","Full Disclosure"],"answer":"Full Disclosure"},{"qID":"6.9|easy","question":"Accountants might recognize losses but not gains in certain situations. For example, the company might write-down the cost of inventory, but will not write-up the cost of inventory. Which principle/guideline is associated with this action?","selection":["Conservatism","Materiality","Monetary Unit"],"answer":"Conservatism"}]},"7":{"category":"FINANCIAL ACCOUNTING","question_set":[{"qID":"7.0|easy","question":"The first section of the statement of cash flows is the OPERATING activities. ","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"7.1|easy","question":"The statement of cash flows explains the changes in cash and cash ON HAND during the specified time interval. ","selection":["Maybe ","False","True "],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"7.2|easy","question":"The word ACCOUNTS is often in the title of liability accounts. ","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"7.3|easy","question":"Prepaid insurance is reported as an ASSET on a company's balance sheet. (","selection":["False","True","Maybe"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"7.4|easy","question":"he main components or elements of the income statement are REVENUES,expenses, gains, and losses. ","selection":["False","Maybe","True"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"7.5|easy","question":"The profitability of a company for a specified period of time is reported on the INCOME statement. ","selection":["False","True ","Maybe"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"7.6|easy","question":"Matching, cost, and full disclosure are examples of the fundamental or basic accounting PRINCIPLES.. ","selection":["False","Maybe","True"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"7.7|easy","question":"The accounting equation is Assets = LIABILITIES + Stockholders' (or Owner's) Equity","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"7.8|easy","question":"Every transaction will have one account being credited and one account being CREDITED ","selection":["True","False","Maybe"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"7.9|easy","question":"SINGLE entry bookkeeping will result in at least two accounts being involved in every transaction. ","selection":["False","True","Maybe"],"answer":"False"}]},"8":{"category":"ADJUSTING ENTRIES","question_set":[{"qID":"8.0|easy","question":"Accounts that are partly income statement accounts and balance sheet accounts are called dual accounts. ","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"8.1|easy","question":"GROOSS PROFIT is equal to Net sales minus cost of goods sold. ","selection":["Maybe ","False","True "],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"8.2|easy","question":"When revenues and expenses are equal for the same accounting period, it is called the matching principle and there is neither a loss or a profit. ","selection":["False","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"8.3|easy","question":"When revenues and expenses are equal for the same accounting period, it is called the matching principle and there is neither a loss or a profit.","selection":["False","True","Maybe"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"8.4|easy","question":"Under the perpetual inventory system, the ending inventory is determined by a physical count and is recorded in the Merchandise Inventory Account.","selection":["False","Maybe","True"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"8.5|easy","question":"Purchaser's description of a cash discount received from a supplier of goods.  ","selection":["Cash discount","Sales discount ","Purchase discount"],"answer":"Purchase discount"},{"qID":"8.6|easy","question":"In general, the accounts in the income statement are ","selection":["Permanent account","Temporary account","Unearned revenues account"],"answer":"Temporary account"},{"qID":"8.7|easy","question":"Which of the following is/are a purpose of adjusting entries?","selection":["To updates the account in the books","To apply the matching principles","All of the above"],"answer":"All of the above"},{"qID":"8.8|easy","question":"Accounts that are partly income statement accounts and balance sheet accounts are called dual accounts","selection":["True","False","Maybe"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"8.9|easy","question":"Under the perpetual inventory system, the ending inventory is determined by a physical count and is recorded in the Merchandise Inventory Account. ","selection":["False","True","Maybe"],"answer":"False"}]},"9":{"category":"BALANCE SHEET","question_set":[{"qID":"9.0|easy","question":"Another name for the balance sheet is ","selection":["Statements of operation","Statement of financial position","Statement of financial income"],"answer":"Statement of financial position"},{"qID":"9.1|easy","question":"The book value of a corporation is the total amount of stockholders' equity reported on the balance sheet. ","selection":["Maybe ","False","True "],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"9.2|easy","question":"The third line of the balance sheet at the end of the year should begin with \"For the Year Ended\". ","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"9.3|easy","question":"The amount reported on the balance sheet for Property, Plant and Equipment is the company's estimate of the fair market value as of the balance sheet date.","selection":["False","True","Maybe"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"9.4|easy","question":"The total amount reported for stockholders' equity is the approximate fair value or net worth of the corporation as of the balance sheet date. ","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"9.5|easy","question":"The balance sheet heading will specify a  ","selection":["Period of time","Point in time ","Service in time"],"answer":"Point in time"},{"qID":"9.6|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for an asset account? ","selection":["Credit","Debit","Balance sheet"],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"9.7|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for liability accounts?","selection":["Debit","Debit and Credit","Credit"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"9.8|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for contra asset accounts?","selection":["Credit","Balance sheet","Debit"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"9.9|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for stockholders' equity and owner's equity accounts? ","selection":["Both Debit and Credit","Debit","Credit"],"answer":"Credit"}]},"10":{"category":"INCOME STATEMENT","question_set":[{"qID":"10.0|easy","question":"If a company's stock is publicly traded, is it a requirement that the earnings per share appear on the income statement? ","selection":["Yes","No",""],"answer":"Yes"},{"qID":"10.1|easy","question":"Are the notes to the financial statements considered to be an integral part of the financial statements? ","selection":["Yes ","No",""],"answer":"Yes"},{"qID":"10.2|easy","question":"","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"10.3|easy","question":"The amount reported on the balance sheet for Property, Plant and Equipment is the company's estimate of the fair market value as of the balance sheet date.","selection":["False","True","Maybe"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"10.4|easy","question":"The total amount reported for stockholders' equity is the approximate fair value or net worth of the corporation as of the balance sheet date. ","selection":["True","Maybe","False"],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"10.5|easy","question":"The balance sheet heading will specify a  ","selection":["Period of time","Point in time ","Service in time"],"answer":"Point in time"},{"qID":"10.6|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for an asset account? ","selection":["Credit","Debit","Balance sheet"],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"10.7|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for liability accounts?","selection":["Debit","Debit and Credit","Credit"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"10.8|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for contra asset accounts?","selection":["Credit","Balance sheet","Debit"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"10.9|easy","question":"What is the normal balance for stockholders' equity and owner's equity accounts?","selection":["Both Debit and Credit","Debit","Credit"],"answer":"Credit"}]},"11":{"category":"BANK RECONCILIATION","question_set":[{"qID":"11.0|easy","question":"Liability From the bank's point of view money the business has in the bank represents this. ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.1|easy","question":"Direct deposits The business can authorise the bank to accept deposits on its behalf. Only when the bank statement is issued does the business receive confirmation of the increase in its deposits. Rent Revenue is commonly deposited directly inot the business's bank account.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.2|easy","question":"Debit column Cheques recorded in the cash payments journal are checked with this column in the bank statement.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.3|easy","question":"Bank statement Document produced by the bank which shows the cash held by a business with the bank. It lists the deposits, withdrawals and balance of the business's bank account over a stated time period usually one month. ","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.4|easy","question":"Overdraft When the business's bank statement shows a Debit balance. This means the business is now an asset to the bank because it owes the bank back the money it has overdrawn its account by.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.5|easy","question":"Checks that have been written by a company but have not yet been charged to the company's checking account are referred to as OUTSTANDING checks.","selection":["True","False ",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.6|easy","question":"A company's receipts from September 30 that get deposited to the company's bank account on October 1st are referred to as deposits IN TRANSIT as of September 30.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.7|easy","question":"A general guide for reconciling the bank statement is Put it where it ISN'T","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"11.8|easy","question":"Your are reconciling the bank statement balance to the cash book balance. Do you need to plus or minus bank transfers from customers?","selection":["Minus","Plus",""],"answer":"Minus"},{"qID":"11.9|easy","question":"You are reconciling the bank statement balance to the cash book balance, do you need to plus or minus bank charges?","selection":["Plus","Minus",""],"answer":"Plus"}]},"12":{"category":"ACCOUNTS PAYABLE","question_set":[{"qID":"12.0|easy","question":"A __________ balance is typical for Accounts Payable. ","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"12.1|easy","question":"The balance in Accounts Payable is decreased with a __________ entry. ","selection":["Debit ","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"12.2|easy","question":"An account payable on the books of the buyer should be an account RECEIVABLE on the books of the seller. ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"12.3|easy","question":"Accounts payable are also known as TRADE  payables.","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"12.4|easy","question":"Suppliers are also referred to as __________. ","selection":["Vendors","Debtors",""],"answer":"Vendors"},{"qID":"12.5|easy","question":"When you make a cash payment to an account supplier you debit or credit accounts payable?","selection":["Debit","Credit ",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"12.6|easy","question":"An accounts payable ledger account would normally have a debit or credit balance?","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"12.7|easy","question":"When you post vouchers to GL, it creates a debit entry to AP and credit to Expense account.  True or False","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"12.8|easy","question":"A purchase return would result in a debit or credit entry to accounts payable?","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"12.9|easy","question":"Another name for accounts payable is?","selection":["Trade debtors","Trade creditors","Creditors"],"answer":"Trade creditors"}]},"13":{"category":"INVENTORY COST OF GOOD SOLD","question_set":[{"qID":"13.0|easy","question":"A retailer's inventory cost should include freight-in on the merchandise purchased with terms FOB shipping point? ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"13.1|easy","question":"The inventory system that does NOT update the Inventory account automatically at the time of each purchase or sales is the PERPETUAL method/system ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"13.2|easy","question":"The account Inventory will appear on the balance sheet as a current asset at an amount that often reflects the SALES VALUE of the merchandise on hand. ","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"13.3|easy","question":"Net Purchases is Gross Purchases minus Purchase Returns and Allowances and SALES DISCOUNT.","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"13.4|easy","question":"The difference between the Cost of Goods Available and the Cost of Goods Sold is STARTING INVENTORY. ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"13.5|easy","question":"When the terms of a sale are FOB destination, legal title to the goods passes to the buyer when they reach the buyerâ€™s place of business.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"13.6|easy","question":"When a purchaser incurs freight costs for the purchase of merchandise, the purchases account is debited.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"13.7|easy","question":"Under FIFO, the cost of goods sold consists of the units with the oldest costs.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"13.8|easy","question":"In a period of inflation, LIFO produces higher net earnings than FIFO.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"13.9|easy","question":"The days in inventory is calculated by dividing the inventory turnover ratio by 365.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"}]},"14":{"category":"DEPRECIATION","question_set":[{"qID":"14.0|easy","question":"Depreciation Expense shown on a company's income statement must be the same amount as the depreciation expense on the company's income tax return.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"14.1|easy","question":"The purpose of depreciation is to have the balance sheet report the current value of an asset.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"14.2|easy","question":"Depreciation Expense reflects an allocation of an asset's original cost rather than an allocation based on the economic value that is being consumed.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"14.3|easy","question":"An asset's useful life is the same as its physical life?","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"14.4|easy","question":"One company might depreciate a new computer over three years while another company might depreciate the same model computer over five years...and both companies are right.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"14.5|easy","question":"Depreciation Expense is shown on the income statement in order to achieve accounting's matching principle.","selection":["True","False ",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"14.6|easy","question":"Accumulated Depreciation will appear as a deduction within the section of the balance sheet labeled as Property, Plant and Equipment.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"14.7|easy","question":"A company may depreciate equipment over 10 years on a straight-line basis for its financial statements, but might use an accelerated method of depreciation over a shorter time period on its income tax return?","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"14.8|easy","question":"Depreciation Expense is sometimes referred to as a noncash expense.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"14.9|easy","question":"Depreciation Expense shown on the financial statements is a precise amount that is continuously refined.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"}]},"15":{"category":"PAYROLL ACCOUNTING","question_set":[{"qID":"15.0|easy","question":"Amounts deducted from gross pay for union subscriptions are represented by a debit or credit to the deductions control account? ","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"15.1|easy","question":"Employee tax and deductions are part of gross pay? ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"15.2|easy","question":"Is gross pay a debit or a credit to the income statement? ","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"15.3|easy","question":"When cash is paid to an employee for net pay, is the entry to the net pay control account a debit or a credit.","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"15.4|easy","question":"When cash is paid to the tax authorities, is the posting to the employees tax control account a debit or credit.","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"15.5|easy","question":"An employer can legally pay a woman different wages than a man based on the nature of the work.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"15.6|easy","question":"Record used in preparing employee's W-2 â†’ Employee's earnings record","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"15.7|easy","question":"Highest-paid 10 percent of workforce can be exempted â†’ Workers' compensation insurance","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"15.8|easy","question":"Anti discrimination orders for employers with contracts involving federal funds â†’ Executive orders","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"15.9|easy","question":"Also known as the Federal Wage and Hour Law â†’ Unemployment insurance taxes","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"}]},"16":{"category":"STOCKHOLHER EQUITY","question_set":[{"qID":"16.0|easy","question":"Dividends appear as an expense on the corporation's income statement. ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"16.1|easy","question":"If the board of directors does not declare the regular quarterly divided on its common stock, the corporation's liabilities will include the omitted dividend. ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"16.2|easy","question":"Treasury stock sales can result in a loss on the corporation's income statement. ","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"16.3|easy","question":"Shares of stock that have been issued and have not been reacquired by the issuing corporation are called OUTSTANDING  shares.","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"16.4|easy","question":"If a corporation has issued only one type of stock, it is COMMON stock.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"16.5|easy","question":"The UNCOMMON date determines which stockholders will receive a declared dividend.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"16.6|easy","question":"The COMMON date is the date on which the corporation records a liability for its quarterly dividend.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"16.7|easy","question":"If a corporation has issued only one type of stock, it is DECLARATION stock.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"16.8|easy","question":"Dividends in arrears occur only on DECLARATION preferred stock.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"16.9|easy","question":"The directors of a corporation appoint BOARD ON DIRECTOR to carry out the corporation's policies and directives.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"}]},"17":{"category":"NONPROFIT ACCOUNTING","question_set":[{"qID":"17.0|easy","question":"Depreciation expense is reported for a not-for-profit organization's equipment and furniture. ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"17.1|easy","question":"Assets released from restrictions will involve two classes of net assets. ","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"17.2|easy","question":"US GAAP requires that the external financial statements of a nonprofit report information by funds. ","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"17.3|easy","question":"Nonprofits are automatically exempt from federal income taxes.","selection":["False","True",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"17.4|easy","question":"It is permissible for a nonprofit to earn a profit.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"17.5|easy","question":"Like other governmental funds, proprietary funds have no emphasis on income measurement.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"17.6|easy","question":"Like other governmental funds, proprietary funds have no emphasis on income measurement.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"False"},{"qID":"17.7|easy","question":"One purpose of an internal service fund is to pool the government's resources for a more efficient operation in carrying out the fund's purpose.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"17.8|easy","question":"Enterprise funds are used for \business-type\" activities","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"},{"qID":"17.9|easy","question":"US GAAP requires that the external financial statements of a nonprofit report information by funds.","selection":["True","False",""],"answer":"True"}]}}}